# ANDRÉS MENESES

UX · PROJECT MANAGEMENT · WEB DEVELOPMENT



WASHINGTON, D.C.



(202)-714-9870



andrenes@gmail.com



https://andrenes.github.io



Digital media professional with experience in user experience design, product-oriented project management, web development, and multi-channel marketing. Strengths include strong communication and collaboration skills, attention to detail, willingness to learn, and management of multiple projects with high levels of efficiency.



# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Web Content Specialist**

11/2017 - PRESENT

#### **American Nurses Association**

- Manage upload and transfer content for web site following style guidelines
- · Work closely with team to deploy properly optimized educational content to web site
- · Ensure consistency of brand and content: text, audio, video
- · Manage workflow and deadlines on multiple simultaneous web content efforts
- Implement online marketing and SEO by adhering to web publishing best practices —formatting, editing, and publishing a variety of content in CMS and social media channels

# **Product Manager**

9/2017 - PRESENT

# iMoveUp!

- Own the vision and the roadmap for user interface design, web development, workflow optimization, and communicating effectively with stakeholders
- Manage product development life cycle—distilling user stories, testing features, managing beta programs, and contributing to product marketing materials
- · Gather user feedback and lead client-facing presentations
- Apply Agile principles in order to uncover essential user needs for optimal UX
- Wireframing and Digital Prototype Development

#### Digital Content Manager

2017 - 08/2017

# American Pharmacists Association

- Conceptualize, develop, and manage online content for PharmacyLibrary.com
- Analyze and make data-aligned improvements to continuously enhance and improve UI/UX
- Oversee workflow management, iterations, content testing, and updates on CMS
- Manage vendors in the areas of design, front end and back end web development
- Coordinate editorial production workflow with authors, proofreaders, and typesetters
- Develop and implement digital strategy ensuring SEO best practices to promote content across web and social media channels

#### **Key Accomplishments**

- Implemented use of project management software Jira and Agile methodologies to more
  effectively manage the life-cycle of projects
- Improved vendor responsiveness by setting clear guidelines, timelines, and communications
- Boosted utilization of online product, Peripheral Brain 2017, by 18% compared to 2016 edition
  by leveraging responsive design, accessibility best practices, Google Analytics, and A/B testing

# Project Manager: Knowledge and Publishing

2005 - 2017

# The World Bank Group

- Provided daily, life-cycle project management of 15+ high-profile publishing projects
- Managed vendor and client deliverables within internal and external digital and print communication channels
- Produced highly-ranked podcast Ideas Unbound with 1,250 average plays per episode
- Maintained critical databases and content management systems for SEO and data analysis to increase audience impact through multi-channel social media marketing
- Worked within a Scrum framework to produce content for Open Knowledge Repository and eLibrary and maintain WordPress and Drupal platforms
- Refined project workflows and deployed metrics to improve productivity
- Participated in cross-team mobile app and web portal working groups
- Designated **team lead** backup due to consistently high performance

#### **Key Accomplishments**

- Implemented business model transition from traditional to new media publishing
- Leveraged digital, social media, and Google analytics for improved UX
- Improved production efficiency by 20% for a World Bank division by implementing new design standards, efficient workflows, and repositioning digital media presence



**SKILLS** 

Bootstrap

Javascript

HTML

Git

CSS

-PROTOTYPING & PROJECT MANAGEMENT -





# **EDUCATION**

# B.S. New Media Publishing - Graphic Communications

Rochester Institute of Technology CUM LAUDE

Codecademy Pro Intensive: Front End Web Development

Codecademy

Codecademy Pro Intensive: Front End App Development

Codecademy

IN PROGRESS
COMPLETION: 12/2017



#### NTERESTS

Chief Blog Editor - Social Media
Manager: Insight Meditation WDC

**Wellness:** Certified meditation, yoga teacher, and CrossFit coach